# JUNYI ZHANG

junyi42zhang@gmail.com GitHub junyi42.com

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests mainly lie in computer vision, deep generative models, and representation learning. I am now focusing on the application of diffusion models, exploring its potential for both generation and perception scenarios. I also have a background in action recognition, self-supervised learning, and modalities such as video, 3D, human motion, and language.

### **EDUCATION**

SEIEE, Shanghai Jiao Tong University	Shanghai, China
Major in Computer Science and Technology; GPA: 3.92 (8/108)	Sept. 2020 - Present
Zhiyuan College, Shanghai Jiao Tong University	Shanghai, China
Major in Zhiyuan Honors Program of Engineering (Top $5\%$ )	Sept. 2020 - Present
SELECTED AWADDS	

### SELECTED AWARDS

Microsoft Research "Stars of Tomorrow" Certificate (Top 10% interns)	2022
Huawei Fellowship (Top 1% in honors program)	2022
National Scholarship (Top 0.2% nationwide, highest honor in China)	2021
Outstanding Undergraduate Scholarship, A Level, SJTU (Top 1%)	2021

### **PUBLICATIONS**

A Tale of Two Features: Stable Diffusion Complements DINO for Zero-Shot Semantic Correspondence Junyi Zhang, Charles Herrmann, Junhwa Hur, Luisa F. Polanía, Varun Jampani, Deqing Sun, Ming-Hsuan Yang. In submission to NeurIPS, 2023. (Received all positive scores with median rating of Accept)

Layout Diffusion: Improving Graphic Layout Generation by Discrete Diffusion Probabilistic Models Junyi Zhang, Jiaqi Guo, Shizhao Sun, Jian-Guang Lou, Dongmei Zhang. In ICCV, 2023.

### Bridging The Isolated Islands in Human Action Understanding

Yong-Lu Li\*, Xiaoqian Wu\*, Xinpeng Liu, Yiming Dou, Yikun Ji, Junyi Zhang, Yixing Li, Xudong Lu, Jingru Tan, Cewu Lu. Under review, 2023.

### Mining Cross-Person Cues for Body-Part Interactiveness Learning in HOI Detection

Xiaoqian Wu\*, Yong-Lu Li\*, Xinpeng Liu, Junyi Zhang, Yuzhe Wu, Cewu Lu. In ECCV, 2022.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# University of California, Merced - Vision Learning Lab

Visiting Student – Supervisor: *Prof.* Ming-Hsuan Yang

Merced, California June 2023 - Present

- Diffusion Models for Semantic Correspondence
  - Explore the internal representations of text-to-image diffusion models for semantic correspondence.
  - o Discover the complementary of Stable Diffusion features and DINOv2 features, based on which achieve state-of-the-art performance under zero-shot setting on a variety of semantic correspondence benchmarks.
  - First-author paper submitted to **NeurIPS'23**. More details at project page.

# Microsoft Research Asia - Data, Knowledge and Intelligence Group

Beijing, China July 2022 - Dec. 2022

Research Intern – Mentor: Dr. Shizhao Sun and Dr. Jian-Guang Lou

# • Diffusion Models for Layout Generation, AI for Design Project

- Study the application of diffusion models in graphic design, especially the graphic layout generation.
- o Develop discrete diffusion models carefully tailored for layout data, achieve state-of-the-art performance in unconditional and conditional generation tasks for several public layout datasets.
- First-author paper accepted by ICCV'23, with potential for product implementation.

# Shanghai Jiao Tong University - Machine Vision and Intelligence Group

Undergraduate Research Intern – Supervisor: Prof. Yong-Lu Li

Shanghai, China Oct. 2021 - Present

### • Diffusion Models for Interactive Motion Generation

- Design a general diffusion models framework for interactive motion generation, including Human-Object Interaction, Hand-Object Interaction, and Human-Human Interaction generation.
- Introduce time-consistency and interaction-awareness to DM by decoupling the added Gaussian noise.

## • Unified Human Action Understanding Project

- Research on unifying multi-modal physical action spaces (2D, 3D, image, video, etc.) to a unified semantic space through the introduction of linguistic structure knowledge.
- Design and conduct experiments to extend our method on video datasets and verify the performance.

## • Human Action Knowledge Engine Project

- o Study on improving Human-Object Interaction (HOI) detection by incorporating human action knowledge.
- Conduct experiments to examine the effect of image depth and multi-person interactions on HOI detection.
- Research results were submitted as co-author in two papers, one of which was accepted by ECCV'22.

### **SKILLS**

- Skills: Python (Pytorch), C/C++, html, css, Linux, LATEX, Assembly language
- Languages: English (TOEFL 105/120), Chinese (Native)